<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>MarkRosario</title>
		<description>linkedin.com/in/mark-anthony-rosario/</description>
		<link>/</link>
		<atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>Single Responsibility Principle</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://preview.redd.it/fgqty05zgoyy.jpg?width=640&amp;amp;crop=smart&amp;amp;auto=webp&amp;amp;s=bb6ce35728aacf199144de322a1455d675fa8077&quot; alt=&quot;image found from reddit&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This image is a perfect example why we need to adhere to SRP (Single Responsibility Principle).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine how terrible would it be to have your elevator disabled due to a light switch that has tight coupling to the main functions of the elevator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Examples like this are easy to understand but when it comes to coding information systems we still find it hard to find the boundaries between abstract concepts
like business rules. My advice to circumvent that is to read business books and work closely with business people until you understand how the yout system works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;..to be continued&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;other-sources-you-can-read&quot;&gt;Other Sources you can read&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oodesign.com/single-responsibility-principle.html&quot;&gt;https://www.oodesign.com/single-responsibility-principle.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://8thlight.com/blog/cory-foy/2012/08/07/thinking-differently-about-srp.html&quot;&gt;https://8thlight.com/blog/cory-foy/2012/08/07/thinking-differently-about-srp.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
				<link>/softwaredesign/2018/11/06/single-responsibility-principle.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/softwaredesign/2018/11/06/single-responsibility-principle.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Blog reboot</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;This new blog at github pages is still in progress. I will be moving my old posts from my decommissioned Wordpress blog soon.
I decided to move to github pages because it is free and so that even if I ever leave Software Development and forget to pay for my domains and hosting, Any piece of information that I would write could still remain (hopefully even long after im dead. lol).
I came across this idea after realizing that software developers at my time are lucky because many prominent people in the development world are still alive and we get knowledge from them but what happens after they die? How will the future generations ensure that knowledge is preserved (for those who do not leave their blogs to corporate ownership)? So i decided that i will keep my own posts in a community-based and free datastore, github pages :).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
				<link>/this%20blog/2018/10/18/blog-reboot.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/this%20blog/2018/10/18/blog-reboot.html</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
